Onyedikachukwu Stephen Ezeamama

39, Gbemisola Adenubi Str., Ago Palaceway, Okota, Isolo, Lagos State | 08139386823 | stehen894@gmail.com |

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Junior Software Developer with 1+ years of experience in the IT and Technology domain looking for a development position. Supportive and enthusiastic team player dedicated to efficiently resolve project issues. Ability and willingness to innovate and learn new technologies, quick learner passionate about development. Seeking to pursue an opportunity with a growing organization that will utilize and enhance my knowledge in software development, and that will provide me with essential growth opportunities.

COMPETENCIES

- Highly organized and efficient.
- Excellent oral and written communication skills.
- Project management skills.
- Good leadership skills.
- Ability to follow instructions and work in a team environment.
- Detail-oriented.
- Strong passion for team spirit and commitment.
- Environmental Awareness and Risk Assessment.
- Ability to learn new software and technologies quickly.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Knowledge of basic coding languages including Angular, C#, Asp.Net MVC, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap.
- Basic Programming experience including Git/GitHub, Microsoft Azure, Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code.
- Good working knowledge of email systems and Microsoft Office software.
- Knowledge of databases including MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Power BI, and operating systems.
- Intermediate Knowledge of Data and Data science.
- Database Management.
- Customer Service.

EDUCATION

B.Eng; Industrial and Production Engineering

2011-2016

Nnamdi Azikiwe University - Awka, Anambra

ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Professional Course (PMP)

April-May 2018

Synergy HR Solutions Ltd – IBRAHIM TAIWO ROAD, KANO.

World Safety Organization Occupational and Environmental Safety and Health Course (WSO HSE Level 1-3)

October 2018

- Health and safety at Work Level 1
- Risk assessment and Practical application Level 2
- Environmental Awareness level 3

Synergy HR Solutions Ltd – IBRAHIM TAIWO ROAD, KANO.

GOOGLE ONLINE DIGITAL SKILLS FOR AFRICA

Online digital marketing.
 GOOGLE NIGERIA.

August 2017

DATA AND DATA SCIENCE

April 2020

• Intro to Data and Data Science 365 DATA SCIENCE.

MICROSOFT AZURE

August 2022

 Cloud Computing MICROSOFT.

PROJECT(S)

MORTGAGE ECOSYSTEM APPLICATION

- Developed a comprehensive mortgage ecosystem application for streaming the loan origination and servicing process, registering new users and organization.
- Integrated with external systems, such as credit bureaus and property valuation services, to automate data retrieval.
- Part of a team of six developers, overseeing project planning, architecture design, and implementation.
- Implemented features for loan application, document management, underwriting.

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

a. GLOBAL TALENT ACQUISITION WEBSITE (ZURI TALENT)

- Built a responsive website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.
- Optimized website performance and conducted unit testing to improve user experience.

b. **CONTACT MANAGER**

- Developed a Contact Manager application using ASP.NET MVC.
- Implemented features for adding, editing, and deleting user records.
- Utilized Entity Framework for data access and SQL Server as the database backend.

c. PAYMENT DETAIL REGISTER

- Created a Payment Detail Register using ASP.NET Web Core API, Angular, C#.
- Implemented features for adding, editing, and deleting user records.
- Integrated with external API for fetching the records.

For more detailed information, code samples, and project demos, please visit my portfolio website: https://fabianprofile.netlify.app/

WORK EXPERIENCE

January 2022 – Till Date

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER; FINTRAK SOFTWARE COMPANY LIMITED – 144A GBAGADA – OWORONSHOKI EXPRESSWAY, ANTHONY, LAGOS

- Collaborate with a team of developers to develop, support, and maintain the Mortgage Ecosystem Application, Core Banking Solution for AG Mortgage Bank using the .NET framework, HTML, CSS, JQUERY, BOOTSTRAP.
- Assisting the development manager with all aspects of software design and coding.
- Participating in daily scrum meetings, sprint planning, unit testing and bug fixes.
- Attending and contributing to company development meetings.
- Monitoring the technical performance of internal systems.
- Learning the codebase and improving my coding skills.
- Gathering information from clients about the program functionality.
- Writing reports.
- Conducting development tests. Working closely with the QA and Product Management teams as well as other developers to ensure quality and punctual software development.

NOVEMBER 2022 - January 2023

JUNIOR .NET DEVELOPER (CONTRACT); SENIOR INTERNET LIMITED – UNIT 13 POPULARS COURT, LENTON LANE, NOTTINGHAM, UNITED KINGDOM

- Collaborate with a team of developers remotely to develop, support, and maintain the River CMS software application using the .NET framework.
- Developed and maintained web application using the Microsoft .NET framework, with expertise in UMBRACO CMS.
- Implemented custom modules within Umbraco to meet client requirements and enhance website functionality.
- Participate in the full software development lifecycle, including requirements analysis, design, coding, testing.
- Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code following coding standards and best practices.
- Debug and troubleshoot issues in software application, identify and resolve defects.

Accomplishments:

- Developed a responsive web application by transforming an already built CRM web design concepts into a fully functional application using the .NET framework.
- Achieved successful project delivery within the specified timeline.

October 2021 - January 2022

CUSTOMER EXPERIENCE EXPERT; UNITED BANK FOR AFRICA PIC – 1664 OYIN JOLAYEMI STREET VICTORIA ISLAND, LAGOS

- Responding promptly to customers through various channels.
- Maintaining a positive, empathetic, and professional attitude toward customers at all times.
- Processing orders, forms, applications, and requests.
- Keeping records of customer interactions, transactions, comments, and complaints.
- Proving feedback on the efficiency of the customer service process.
- Ensure customer satisfaction and provide professional customer support.

Accomplishments:

- Implemented a CSR script to be used for new customers that increased efficiency by 20%.
- Provided a personalized services to each customer, resulting in 5-star feedback from clients.
- Trained 10+ call center agents in performing outreach work, as part of their induction process.
- Provided excellent services to an irate corporate customer, as a result, retained his business.
- Successfully built a sustainable relationship with customers, going the extra mile in all conversations.

July 2019 – September 2021

PRODUCTION ENGINEER; ELEGANZA INDUSTRIAL CITY LIMITED - 38km IBEJU-LEKKI EXPRESSWAY OFF EPE, LAGOS.

- Provide engineering support for production and maintenance activities to ensure maximum production.
- Evaluate current production activities and make recommendations for improvements.
- Checking the accuracy of tools and quality of materials used for manufacturing the products.
- Establish safety procedures and environmental regulations for employees.
- Ensure efficient operation of equipment by calling for repairs; evaluating new equipment and techniques.
- Develop operating instructions and equipment specifications for production activities and prepare effective production schedules and ensure compliance to all company policies.

Accomplishments:

- Provided training and guidance to team members to accomplish production goals.
- Devised ideas and strategies to resolve the challenges in manufacturing the products through
 decreasing Production time, ensure the right material and component supplies at the least cost,
 eliminate wastage and maintain quality in the final product, replaced the worn-out machine parts
 with new ones or giving services to the old machines on time and by using tools of good quality and
 raw materials.
- Also, devised strategies for improving teamwork and communication among members of team projects.

March 2019 - July 2019

DATA ANALYST; FLOW COMPUTER SYSTEMS - 49, SHOTINOYE STREET, PAPA AJAO, LAGOS.

- Physical Verification and Tagging of Assets.
- Data gathering and auditing of the Fixed Assets.
- Record the assets data into the Personal Data Assistant (PDA) Scanner.
- Transfer and review the verified data using the Archibus software.
- Data Reconciliation.

Accomplishments:

Introduced the Asset Template Sheet format to review and ensure that all the recorded inventory data in the Personal Data Assistant (PDA) Scanner are correct and accurate at the end of the project. Also, introduced the set restriction method by using the Archibus application to make work easier and faster when reviewing the transferred data.

November 2017- December 2018

SALES REPRESENTATIVE; TIMGREAT PHARMACEUTICAL VENTURES LIMITED – OBAFEMI AWOLOWO ROAD, MALLAM KATO, KANO.

- Supervision, supply and distribution of pharmaceutical products to clients/customers.
- Sales, documentation and inventory of pharmaceuticals.
- Ensuring smooth sales process daily whilst maintaining good customer care relations.

Accomplishments:

Facilitated improved sales by implementing good customer management strategies.

December 2017 - October 2018

NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS (NYSC)

MATHEMATICS TEACHER; GOVERNMENT DAY SECONDARY SCHOOL- KUNDUM, SUMAILA, Kano.

- Teaching students the rudimentary principles of Mathematics
- Imparting moral values with a view of grooming future leaders

- Preparing lecture notes, exams and tests
- Developing and implementing innovative ways to improve learning experience

Accomplishments:

• Pioneered the reintroduction and implementation of extracurricular activities such as debates and sporting activities to improve cognitive reasoning and learning experience.

September 2017 - November 2017

SANITATION SUPERVISOR and ASSISTANT FINANCIAL OFFICER; LEILAS PLACE - IRE-AKARI, ISOLO, Lagos

- Inspect equipment for cleanliness and safety at various times daily or weekly.
- Scheduling sanitation employees and making sure there is appropriate coverage at all times.
- Overseeing responsibilities carried out by the sanitation team while performing my duties and making sure tasks are completed successfully.
- Assist the Account manager with month end close process ensuring all entries are posted timely and accurately.
- Keeping proper record of Sales' inflow and outflow.

Accomplishments:

• Led reforms which led to improved sanitary measures

May 2015 - October 2015

INDUSTRIAL TRAINEE; ALAN DAVIES TECHNICAL COMPANY- OKOTA, LAGOS

- Drilling and gear cutting
- Top Cylinder resurfacing.
- General re-conditioning of engine block and motorcycle hobs.
- Metal joining processes and maintenance of cutting and drilling equipment.
- Project planning and execution.

Accomplishments:

Introduced the idea of replacing of motorcycle hobs with trailer rim hobs which reduced maintenance and operation cycle time, making the process more efficient and affordable for customers. Came up with various marketing strategies such as distribution of hand flyers which led to increase in number of customs

- Preparing lecture notes, exams and tests
- Developing and implementing innovative ways to improve learning experience

Accomplishments:

• Pioneered the reintroduction and implementation of extracurricular activities such as debates and sporting activities to improve cognitive reasoning and learning experience.

September 2017 - November 2017

SANITATION SUPERVISOR and ASSISTANT FINANCIAL OFFICER; LEILAS PLACE - IRE-AKARI, ISOLO, Lagos

- Inspect equipment for cleanliness and safety at various times daily or weekly.
- Scheduling sanitation employees and making sure there is appropriate coverage at all times.
- Overseeing responsibilities carried out by the sanitation team while performing my duties and making sure tasks are completed successfully.
- Assist the Account manager with month end close process ensuring all entries are posted timely and accurately.
- Keeping proper record of Sales' inflow and outflow.

Accomplishments:

• Led reforms which led to improved sanitary measures

May 2015 - October 2015

INDUSTRIAL TRAINEE; ALAN DAVIES TECHNICAL COMPANY- OKOTA, LAGOS

- Drilling and gear cutting
- Top Cylinder resurfacing.
- General re-conditioning of engine block and motorcycle hobs.
- Metal joining processes and maintenance of cutting and drilling equipment.
- Project planning and execution.

Accomplishments:

Introduced the idea of replacing of motorcycle hobs with trailer rim hobs which reduced maintenance and operation cycle time, making the process more efficient and affordable for customers. Came up with various marketing strategies such as distribution of hand flyers which led to increase in number of customs

REFEREE

Mr. Olawale Owolabi

Managing Director Flow Computer Systems 0802-332-8169

Mrs. Shaibu Roselyn

Managing Director Leilas Place 0803-320-0487

Mr. Taiwo Abioye

Senior Software Engineer FinTrak Software Company Limited 0814-666-3777